Speaker: I’d say my parents were pretty strict.
I mean, they were…they were very strict about some things in particular; not so much about,
I don’t know, playing outside, or things like that.
In fact, I remember we used to go off and play all day
and they wouldn’t know where we were or care what time we came back,
so long as we didn’t miss a meal or something like that.
But they were very strict about studying.
They were very demanding: they wanted us to always be top of the class;
they’d be very upset if we didn’t do well.
On the other hand, they didn’t use to control how much homework we were doing,
they never helped us with our homework, they just assumed we would be getting on with it,
and they were very angry if we didn’t get – well, when I say ‘they’,
my father much more than my mother – would be very angry if we didn’t do well in exams.
My mother would be disappointed, but my father would be angry,
and I remember with my A levels I got two As and a B, and he didn’t say
‘Well done’, he just said, ‘Why did you get that B?’ And, er…so, my dad was controlling.
I mean, he was pretty authoritarian and he controlled our tastes
– well, he tried to control our tastes
– in all sorts of things, in the sense that he thought we should agree with everything he liked.
So, he didn’t approve of football, but he liked tennis, so watching tennis was fine,
but watching football wasn’t.
And he adored classical music, but loathed pop music, and I remember that, er,
if he came in and my sister and I were watching a programme like Top of the Pops on television,
he would immediately switch it off, and I think he actually broke some records
that we’d bought of Beatles songs or something like that.